Darn it. I'm gonna be late again.
Great, right?
I am proud, but I am torn about soccer. It's taking you away from me.
Oh?
oh not again no more drinking with customers
oh what's so important that you're calling me now earlier on the phone that was your mom right
i heard what she said oh that was nothing what did she mean by soccer's taking you away
sounds kind of ominous did you talk to her at all about it well did you no i haven't yet she went
straight to the bar afterwards for work so i really didn't get a chance to ask her are you even a little
curious you think your own mom would be happy for you do not tell me you snuck off to tokyo to attend
the espirion tryouts without getting her permission what a disrespectful child first of all what i do
or don't tell my mom is none of your business and why are we even talking about this did you call
to interrogate me ashito if that's the espirian manager's sister on the phone can i ask something
i'm looking over the meal plan she gave you and it's actually really well thought out
i'm curious why you have it though are you supposed to be following this exact diet
no feel free to adjust it however you want to it's just an example really mainly you want to make sure
he's eating meals that are balanced and nutritious it's not enough to focus on your
body soccer players need to be smart too it's best if you find foods that'll help him build brains and
brawn i've gotta admit i'm pretty proud of my meal plan ashito's big bro uh-huh good to know coming up
with meal ideas is a hassle might be easier just to follow this you won't regret it i put a lot of
thought into it it might even be my best work so anyway hey listen it's hana right i remember you
saying that that was your name i think not that i don't appreciate it but why go through all of this
it's for me who knows guess it's a mystery
back to what i was saying
you really should try to talk to your mom about it
this is important
where does she get off calling in the dead of night to lecture me about my own mom
even if she does have a point
i'm torn about soccer it's taking you away from me
oh my god stupid stupid stupid why did you say that you idiot
i'm pathetic
you still there hello oh i can hear you breathing you know
it's funny no matter what happened mom's never been like that didn't know she had it in her
honestly surprised the heck out of me
yeah
i didn't think she could be anything but strong now that i know how she actually feels
i can't go to tokyo
i've made a decision okay
well apologizing outright would feel weird kinda
so maybe
it'd be better to act normal for now
then we could sit down and talk about it
hana
look the reason i play
why i want this so bad is for her
if i go pro i'll make a ton of money
and then she won't have to work as hard
i know myself i'm not a smart guy
so this is my best shot at earning enough money to make my mom's life easier
that's why i have to go pro no matter what
but
if running off to tokyo's gonna be hard on mom
i'll have to come up with some other
i'm home you little bastards
wait hold on mom
what the hell are you brats up to
that better not be a phone i see there
just who are you calling in the middle of the night
oh uh hi mom we're actually on the phone with someone from
esperion who called ashito about something
she called us so we're not being charged for it
but we're still paying for electricity you idiot
how many times have i said
as soon as it gets dark outside you should head straight to bed
you're too young to be having late calls with the lights on
and doing it while i'm at work behind my back
oh crap we're still on the line with hana
pardon
pardon you're calling from esperion right next time don't call so late at night
yes of course
oh yeah
one more thing while you're here
what would it cost to send him to tokyo
what other expenses are there
things like school housing and food
if it's possible i would like to get a full breakdown
you mean from me
hmm hold on you two she sounds young
are you sure she's from the club
i am i promise
just a second i've got it right here
i can help answer any questions you may have
for sure
and so over the next few days
hana and some other officials from the club
talked mom through all the ins and outs of me joining esperion
all the details were quickly falling into place
i was going back to tokyo
and one step closer to my dream
although in all that time
no matter how hard i tried
i never got the chance to tell mom how i really felt
and spring finally arrived
hey mom i need to talk to you
oh hey did you just get taller again
uh oh um yeah i guess i did
i knew it
well that's puberty for you
right
there's no need to pack stuff you've outgrown
also for your shoes
you still wear size nines
oh yeah nines
hey mom wait a sec
and done
that's the last of it
you're officially packed up
ashito
good luck
okay
shun's gonna take you to the station
in the end
for those of you who weren't aware
ashito aoi has made the difficult decision to attend a school in tokyo
where he's accepted an offer to join their youth soccer club
it's quite rare for one of our students to go to a high school so far away
of course i know aoi will do his best to make our school proud
unfortunately his club's training sessions are set to start soon
so he'll be leaving for tokyo today
which means he won't be graduating with you all
of course i know everyone here is going to miss our aoi dearly
even though he has to go catch his train soon
he wanted to drop in and say goodbye to the class
one last time before he left
well isn't that just wonderful
so how about a round of applause
so how'd your final farewell go
you okay
you kept the fact that you're leaving today a secret until the last minute
i don't get it
being sad or gloomy doesn't suit me
especially with the soccer club guys
you know that i can't stand long tearful goodbyes
trust me i saved us a whole lot of hassle
also think i've had enough of seeing them look sad because of my choices
it's better this way
hey listen
if there's anything you need while you're in tokyo
just let me know okay
i'll try to help
sure
i can't help but feel excited
we've been planning this with the people from the club for the last six months
and yet i can't even imagine what your life in tokyo is going to be like
ashito
when you get there
could you please thank hana for me
sending you a customized meal plan every week was incredibly helpful
not to mention everything else
she always did her best to answer our questions or ease our concerns
and if there was anything complicated she'd break it down and explain it to us
i know mom really appreciated all of her work too
that's so nice
i'm glad there's somebody she's listening to
i never got a chance to talk to her and now i'm leaving damn it
every time i try to have a serious conversation she changed the subject
what was i supposed to do
and she didn't even come to see you off
i'm surprised
i'm not it's just like her to do this kind of thing
oh well whatever it really is too bad that i didn't get to talk to her
but i'm going pro
even if i have to crawl on my hands and knees to get there
that's why no matter what happens i can't stop moving forward
i've been thinking about mom so much
that i let soccer slip by the wayside
how pathetic can i get no more
now i'm done worrying i'll keep going
i've decided i'm not gonna be sad
when i leave here i'm gonna do it smiling
from this point onward i won't let myself be weak
you're late
man you're telling me that i could have taken it easy instead of rushing
but it was totally worth it to see the look on your face
for sure
it would have been really lame if we showed up after he left
it's a good thing you got here because we were getting pretty tired of waiting for you
you guys
but don't you all have class right now
well after you dropped the news on us and tried to sneak off
of course as his coach i can't let him just leave like that
so soccer team members i give you all my permission
get together and you all go after ashito
um sir we'd like to go too
nice drive but you don't get to just cut and run
too bad
who are you trying to fool with that attitude huh
we could totally tell you were faking it
you were supposed to be impressed by that
crap come on smile
oh man what am i gonna do with you guys
let's take some pictures
truth is
i wanted to keep playing with you in high school
yeah
let's play again one day
ashito good luck out there
smile
well this is it everybody
i have to keep smiling
i was able to keep playing soccer
all thanks to you guys
so i'm gonna become the best player in the world
don't worry shun
i'll do my best to make you proud too
oh like did you pack a lunch for me
something from mom
she wanted you to have it
but she said to wait until you were on the train to open it
it looks like a letter
it's got something else in it too
what's more
this box has got some weight to it
who knows what kind of stuff she put inside
how many times do i have to tell you before you remember
always make eye contact
always say what you mean
and whatever you do
don't be an indecisive person
now that i think about it
she's not exactly the type to write somebody a letter
wait if that's the case
does that mean she wrote something she couldn't say to my face
dear ashito
i am disowning you
you decided to run off to tokyo like a complete nutter moron
you didn't spare a thought for our family's finances
therefore you're officially no longer a part of this family
you're dead to us
never come back here
i filled the box with your only possessions
your collection of pervy magazines
well i think i could handle something like that
the only thing i'm worried about
is that this letter is mom's way of saying she'll miss me
or that she's sad i'm leaving
oh whatever
dear ashito
first things first
i'm sorry i didn't come to see you off
also
i know that you've been trying to talk to me about something for the last six months
i'm sorry for brushing you off
thing is
being sad or gloomy just doesn't suit me
and frankly i'm a little selfish
i'm sorry
again
there's a bank book and a card in the envelope
you can use the money for your day-to-day living expenses
don't worry about your tuition and club fees
i'll be taking care of those
though i wasn't sure what else you might need
once you got settled in at your new school
i still have my bar to think about
and if i kept this money i'd probably spend it on something stupid
that's why
i figured it'd be best to give it to you now
you better not waste it
mom
i know i said this earlier
but i'm sorry again for ignoring you whenever you wanted to talk to me
to tell you the truth
i didn't want to have that conversation
because i already knew what you were going to tell me
because that night
the reason i play
why i want this so bad
is for her
i heard what you said
when you were on the phone
that was enough for me
thank you ashito
but seriously
i can't have you saying that kind of thing to my face
you get it right
wait no way
you're kidding me
mom what the heck
why are you getting sappy all of a sudden
this is too much
i told myself that i'd leave with a smile on my face
i'm sorry i couldn't afford to buy you new cleats before
so as a farewell gift
would you look at that your mom saved up enough to buy real gear
remember how you used to be crazy poor
the only thing i'm worried about is how short-tempered you can be
but i know that it's proof that you've grown into an earnest and sincere person
you take a lot after me
if you're concerned about our finances
don't be
i'm your mother
it's my job to support you in whatever you want to do
plus with you gone
there's one less mouth to feed
don't forget there are others around you too
people who are rooting for you
and who lift you up when you need help
you have lots of people who are in your corner
and i'm sure you'll meet even more in tokyo
be grateful for their support
and don't get a big head
one more thing
i don't know too much about soccer
so whether you're good at it or not
or if you'll go pro or not
none of that really matters to me
honestly
it wouldn't change the way i feel
because whether you succeed or not
i will always be so proud of you ashito
i've been proud of you ever since you were born
please don't ever forget that
make sure you're eating well
and don't get hurt okay
i know playing soccer makes you happy
so pour your heart and soul into it
do your best
mom
OO
Thank you.
Next time on Awashi, first fan.